SUDHAMS

2A, Deshma Green Park, Subashri Nagar, Mugalivakkam, Ch-125 | **Phone**: +91 9176915960 **Email:** sudhavstorage@gmail.com | **Website**: https://sudha108.github.io/resume

Profile

2+ experience in **Quality Assurance** and **Test Automation** in Ruby, Javascript and Python. Fair knowledge in API testing, Cucumber, Protractor, Pytest, JMeter, Docker, Jenkins, Git, and Databases. A collaborative team player with the ability to learn new concepts and software quickly, excellent communication, leadership and interpersonal skills.

Experience

Sept 2017 - Sept 2019 (2yrs)

Fourkites, Chennai - Quality Assurance Engineer

Fourkites uses a proprietary algorithm combined with the world's broadest data network to predict when shipments will arrive at scheduled stops, monitor load temperatures and analyze enterprise supply chain data. Predictive Capacity Management and Lane Connect provides the opportunity for shippers to collaborate with each other and share their assets to optimise their backhauls.

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Initiated API Test Automation in the project I was working with configurable and reusable methods for APIs and DB validations using Cucumber and RSpec in Ruby as a fresher with minimal guidance.
 Integrated with TestRails for test case management and Google Sheets for collecting API data and metrics
- Automated demo data creation via a cron running on **Jenkins** with self-interest
- Initial contributor to the company-wide almost scriptless test automation framework which uses **Nodejs**, **Protractor** & Cucumber
- Optimised several functions in the framework and wrote generic methods for validations and database querying in MongoDB and MySQL and helpers for integrating with TestRails, AWS-SQS
- Experience in **Agile** Methodologies and also have handled releases as a single QA resource
- Initiated preparation of **Test Plans** in the team for every release to capture risks and plan for mitigation
- Recognised in monthly all hands several times for taking up ownership
- Mentored 3 interns to test in an agile manner and capturing corner cases
- Used **Postman Collection Runners** for testing in bulk along with scripts for validations
- Improvised load testing in JMeter with BeanShell scripts for data manipulations
- Familiar with Jira, Confluence, TestRails, Git, Docker, Jenkins, Spark, AWS-SQS, AWS-S3, AWS-EB, ElasticSearch, Log Entries Dashboard, Postgres, MySql, MongoDB, Neo4j
- Expertise in location-based data preparation especially in the US and tested the product like a layman
- Interned initially for about 7 months with full QA responsibility during college

Oct 2019 - Sept 2020 (1yr)

Fourkites, Chennai - Test Automation Engineer

- Stabilised daily regression results to a good extent by analyzing and fixing a lot of automation issues and also handled different environment-related scenarios
- Good at debugging and fixing issues in automation
- Automated more than 400 cases in Protractor framework (30+ in mail validations, 20+ in database validations, 200+ in api validations) within a short period of time
- Improvised protractor automation code by modularising and simplifying common functions. For example, combined methods that create similar data using ui and api
- Wrote more than 25 generic steps in protractor framework which can be reused across several modules by just replacing variables and QAs have been able to automate test cases with 0% coding effort using them
- Automated more than 50 test cases with **Pytest** framework written in python and contributed to general utilities such as logging, polling (check for conditions in intervals of time)

Other Technical Skills

- Designed and built web applications with plain HTML, CSS, plain Javascript, Angular, SCSS
- Built Apis with plain NodeJs and Postgres and also built using express and mongoose frameworks
- Familiar with shell scripting, npm, Asynchronous Javascript, CSS animations, Puppeteer
- Experience in using Eclipse, Webstorm, Android Studio and Visual Studio Code IDEs
- Have deployed personal applications using Heroku as well as firebase

Personal Projects

Application Blocking for Group of Users (Ablo) - *Android Application* (B.E. Final year college project)

- **Description:** For a group of users with an admin, the application blocks blacklisted mobile apps for subordinate users on excessive usage during working hours as configured by the admin
- Technology: PHP, Java, MySQL, Android: Broadcast Receivers, Shared Preferences, Volley Library
- Presented the project at an **International Conference** in Chennai

Education

August 2014 - April 2018

Dhanalakshmi College of Engineering, Chennai - B.E.(CSE) - 7.74 CGPA

- Class Representative for 2 years
- Been a member of Rotaract and Inspire club and conducted events
- Workshops: IoT (Microsoft), Embedded Linux, Python (Infosys)
- Courses: Introduction to OS (NPTEL), Programming in Java (360 Ripples)
- Participated in open house exhibitions and symposiums
- The first student in the batch to get placed in the entire college

April 2002 - April 2014

Kendriya Vidyalaya Minambakkam, Chennai - 9.4 CGPA in 10th & 82% in 12th

- Participated and ranked among the top 30% at school level in Science and Green Olympiads
- Participated in Inter-school Social Science Exhibitions & Regional National Children's Science Congress

Personal Information

Languages I know

English - Speak, Read, Write

Hindi - Speak, Read, Write

Tamil - Speak, Read

Kannada - Speak, Read, Write

Tulu - Speak

Hobbies

- Painting and sketching
- Writing stories and publish them online in Wattpad